kettlebells are arguably the most
versatile piece of gym equipment since
most of the workouts you're going to be
doing with one are going to require your
entire body to be involved while one
single kettlebell isn't necessarily
large adding multiple to your home gym
can be a bit of a hassle since you know
they're probably going to take up too
much floor space this is where
adjustable kettlebells like this bad boy
from rep Fitness really come into play
I've been swinging this cast iron friend
of mine around a lot lately so you know
what time it is let's dive into a full
review
thank you
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
review I've got the rep Fitness
adjustable kettlebell in this video I'm
going to tell you everything you need to
know about this piece of equipment from
the price and the features some pros and
cons I've noticed and of course who
should or maybe should not add one of
these to their home gym
before I get going with all that though
we've reviewed a whole lot of
kettlebells on barbin.com so if you want
to browse our best list just go and
search bar band best kettlebells you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
foreign
off with what I really enjoy about this
kettlebell and first of all we gotta
talk about the compact nature of it so
it's pretty much the same size as your
you know traditional kettlebell but it's
going to replace six individual
kettlebells which is really nice so
within this cast iron shell which real
quick this is one solid piece of cast
iron so you don't have to worry about
you know the Bell right here going
flying across the room as you're doing
your kettlebell swings all right so once
again you know this weighs 15 pounds on
its own and then you have five
individual cast iron weight plates
within it that also weigh five pounds so
in total this is going to range from 15
pounds up to 40 pounds so there's a lot
of Versatility right here and that's
just nice for obvious reasons and I also
really like how underneath right here
there's a rubber bottom and that's just
going to protect your floors which
definitely you know want to protect our
living space right also it's super easy
for you to adjust the weights all you
got to do is push down on this knob
right here select the weight increment
you want and then lift it up and these
plates are gonna you know stay on the
ground and you're good to go so that's
obviously really nice and they're also
competitively priced and there's three
different buying options for you to
choose from so odds are you know most
athletes are going to find a specific
kettlebell that meets their needs
[Music]
now with all those great things being
said there are a few potential cons that
you might run into and first of all we
gotta talk about the max weight which is
53 pounds now it's honestly you know
pretty average across the market but you
know if you're somebody who is you know
an avid kettlebell athlete and you you
know need heavier weight than that well
you're just gonna have to go and snag
you know a traditional kettlebell also I
mentioned they're competitively priced
but they're definitely not the cheapest
option on the market so you know if you
don't want to spend the amount of money
that these are which I'm going to talk
about in just a second hang tight you
can always find a cheaper one out there
and then lastly this adjustment
mechanism is in fact made of plastic so
you obviously run the potential of you
know wear and tear and accelerated rate
as opposed to a kettlebell that use you
know cast iron within it and you know
that just might be a turn off for some
people
[Music]
okay so let's talk about money now as I
just said that I would do the cheapest
option out of the three that are
available on the rep Fitness website is
gonna be the 8 to 16 kilogram Bell
that's gonna run you around 150 bucks
the 20 to 40 pound bell I have right
here can run you around 160 and then the
16 to 24 kilogram Bell that's going to
run you around 210 now you're not able
to finance this purchase but shipping is
free which if you've ever had to pay for
shipping for a kettlebell I already know
you view that as a massive win right
there so that's really nice and once
again you know these are not the
cheapest option that are on the market
but I do think they provide excellent
value you know it's super easy to adjust
the weight they're going to replace the
multiple kettlebells obviously and then
also you know this cast iron build right
here really gives you that traditional
feeling of your you know standard cast
iron kettlebell
foreign
okay so let's switch gears for a second
and talk about the build and some of the
features with the rep Fitness adjustable
kettlebell let's talk about the handle
first the diameter is right around 33
millimeters and that's all across right
here which is really nice and I'm pretty
positive it's going to be the exact same
regardless of which you know weight
option you decide to purchase this is in
fact a cast iron kettlebell which is
really nice it's one solid piece though
too so this handle and the actual Bell
down here you know they're one single
piece that's really nice there's no
welding or anything so it's really going
to hold up in the long run the weight
plates are also cast iron which is nice
but remember this is plastic right here
this adjustment mechanism in the long
run though I think durability is going
to be pretty much fine so I don't think
it's too much of an issue to worry about
I really like this rubber bottom right
here too you know it's just going to be
really nice you know you're working on
out on hardwood floors or you know
whatever just in your home it's going to
be a good thing you know just protect
your flooring at least a little bit
right I also really like how this does
in fact have a powder coat on it you
know it's going to give you a really
solid grip on its own it also should mix
well with chalk if you know if that's
your preference and then you know it's
going to add a little bit of Chip
resistance as well and then that just
also just you know means that you have a
nice traditional feeling that you get
with a standard cast iron kettlebell and
then lastly I just want to touch on the
three different buying options one more
time so you have that 8 to 16 kilogram
Bell the 20 to 40 pound bell I have
right here and the 16 to 24 kilogram
options so that's just nice you know
there is some variety with your
purchasing all right so I just wanted to
go ahead and you know show this
kettlebell in action I guess you could
say and just kind of demonstrate you
know really how quick it is for you to
adjust the weight on the fly so right
now we've got it on 40 pounds I'm gonna
go ahead and knock out some kettlebell
swing for y'all and so as you're
swinging it you'll hear a little bit of
the rattle of the plates but it has not
affected me negatively whatsoever during
my workouts so just go ahead just grab
this bad boy
and I don't know if you can hear that or
not but there's a little bit of a wobble
now just go ahead and see this right
here we're on 40. we're gonna go down to
25 real quick
boom this plates are just right there
and now you're free to switch up your
workout
and similar to the swings you can hear a
little bit of a rattle right there but
it's not knocking me off of my you know
flow or movement pattern or anything
like that and then look
set it back
put it back on 40. everything's here and
you're good to store this you know
essentially anywhere you know and just
tuck it in a corner or whatever
and you're good to go okay so who should
purchase the rep Fitness adjustable
kettlebells so first of all your title
in space this is going to be really nice
for you you know once again this
individual kettlebell replaces six
kettlebells that's obviously a good
thing but you know it doesn't require
much space to be stored you can you know
stash it in a closet put it in the
corner of a room really you know
opportunities are endless and that's
obviously a really good thing there's
also you know three different buying
options so essentially you know all
athletes are going to be able to find
you know one of these adjustable
kettlebells that meets their needs which
is also a really really nice thing right
there and then lastly you know the
construction you know is cast iron
kettlebell it's a really structurally
sound product so if that's something
that you you know prioritize in your gym
equipment I think you're gonna be really
happy here
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to add one of these to their
home gym and I think we should talk
about money I personally think these
offer excellent value but at the same
time they're not the cheapest available
kettlebells on the market so you know if
you want to save some money you
certainly can and then also you know do
have a little bit of plastic right here
you know it's centralized with this
adjustment mechanism but there's still
plastic involved so you know if you want
to avoid that all together there are
other options out there that you know
ditch plastic entirely so definitely
keep that in mind too
[Music]
that's all I got for y'all today on the
rep Fitness adjustable kettlebells
regardless of which weight option you
choose these are going to save you both
money and space in your home gym which
is something that I just personally love
I also love the fact that they are made
from one single piece of cast iron right
here and it's super easy to adjust your
weight
thanks for hanging out with me y'all I
hope this video was super helpful and
that I was able to answer any questions
you may have about this product now as
always keep your eyes peeled for my next
video but for now it's something I want
you to do I want you to head over to
barbin.com that's because we have a full
written article ready for you to read
just go ahead and search bar Bend rep
Fitness adjustable kettlebell review
it's going to pull right up for you and
you'll be able to read everything we
talked about here today and who knows
you might even learn something new I'll
catch y'all next time
[Music]